Hey, Cully, would you look who's here?
嘿, Cully, 你看看谁来了？
Any Quarks?
还有夸克吗？
- CULLY: Yes, one.  - JAMIE: Hmm.
- 是的, 有一个  - 唔
CULLY: No, there's more. Can't quite see,
不, 还有好些, 看不太清楚
but I think they're working at something
just outside the building.
但我觉得它们就在楼外面干什么活
JAMIE: Let's have a look.
我们来看一眼
They don't seem to have harmed anybody.
他们似乎没有伤害谁
Well, Balan isn't there.
好, Balan 不在那里
He's probably working somewhere else.
他很可能在别的什么地方干活
- Look, Cully...  - What now?
- 看, Cully...  - 现在怎样？
We can't just let them stay up there, can we?
我们不能让他们待在那上面, 是吧？
- Well, what can we do?
- Get them down here with us.
- 那, 我们怎么办？  - 把他们弄下来跟我们待一起
- But what about the Quarks?  - Well, we'll...
- 但夸克怎么对付？  - 这样, 我们...
Here we go again.
我们又来了
- Operate! -(WHIRRING)
开动！
- Doctor? - Hmm?
- 博士?  - 唔？
What are they doing?
他们在做什么？
They're drilling.
在钻孔
Well, yes, I know that, but what for?
啊, 是, 我知道这个, 但钻孔做什么？
Hmm?
嗯？
I don't think they want to take
anything out of the Earth, Zoe,
我觉得他们不是想从地里取什么东西出来, Zoe
rather put something into it.
而是要放什么东西进去
- Well, what?  - Well, if I'm right...
- 但, 是怎么呢？  - 哦, 如果我是对的...
Oh, no!
噢, 不！
(MOUTHING)
(QUARK BLEEPING)
Excuse me...
原谅我...
QUARK: Do not move!
不许动!
Oh!
哦!
(QUARK ALARM BUZZING)
- Right, Cully!  - Quick, follow me!
- 好了, Cully!  - 快, 跟着我！
- Don't just stand there, go on!  - Quick!
- 别在那里傻站着, 走啊！  - 快！
Cease drilling!
停止钻取！
A Quark is being attacked! Follow!
一个夸克被袭击了！跟上！
Quarks, search and destroy!
夸克们, 搜索、消灭！
Quark, where are the prisoners?
夸克, 那些囚徒都去哪儿了？
QUARK: Out of action.
有故障
No recorded data.
没有数据记录
They can't be far away. They must be hiding.
他们不可能跑远, 肯定是躲起来了
Quarks, search and destroy!
夸克们, 搜索、消灭！
Command countermanded!
撤回命令！
Why has the drilling stopped again, Toba?
钻孔为什么又停下来了, Toba?
The prisoners have attacked
a Quark and escaped!
那些囚徒袭击了一个夸克, 然后逃跑了！
And once again you've dropped
everything to hunt them!
而你又一次放下了所有事情去追他们！
I have just completed calculating
the remaining power levels of the Quark force.
我刚刚对夸克的剩余能量值完成了计算
Thanks to your foolish actions,
they are dangerously low!
多亏了你的愚蠢行为, 它们的值现在低得危险！
All efforts must now be concentrated
on completing our mission.
现在所有的精力必须聚焦在完成我们的任务上
And if they attack us again?
但如果他们再次袭击我们呢？
The Quark's power must be conserved.
夸克的能量必须保留
Complete the drilling operation!
完成钻孔操作！
Command accepted.
命令已接受
Toba, the primitives will not go unpunished.
Toba, 这些原始人不能不罚
Fleet Leader has just confirmed
舰队首领刚刚证实了
the Dulcians are unsuitable for slave labour.
Dulkis 星人不适合作为奴隶劳工
They will die with their planet.
他们会与他们的星球一起灭亡
Good.
很好
So the sooner we complete the drilling operations,
所以我们越早完成钻孔工作
the sooner they will die.
他们死得越早
Quark, follow!
夸克, 跟上！
(QUARK BLEEPING)
They've gone.
他们走了
That was very rash of you, Jamie.
Those Quarks are appallingly dangerous.
你那样可真是鲁莽, Jamie, 那些夸克可不是一般的危险
Och, they're not so terrible.
噢, 他们并没那么可怕
You know, we dropped a rock on one earlier.
你知道吗, 早先我们用石头砸了一个
Hey, where's Balan? Why wasn't he...
嘿, Balan 在哪儿？为什么他没...
He's dead, Cully. The Dominators killed him.
他死了, Cully, 统领者杀了他
Oh, no! If only we'd managed to get him away, too.
哦, 不！我们要是设法也把他救走就好了
You did your best, Cully.
你尽力了, Cully
It's thanks to you and Jamie
that the rest of us are safe.
得感谢你和 Jamie, 我们其他人才安全了
DOCTOR: I'm afraid not.
Nowhere on the island is safe.
恐怕没有．这个岛上哪里都不安全
Nowhere on the entire planet, come to that!
这整个星球哪里都不安全!
You see, we heard the Dominators say
是这样, 我们听到统领者说
that the Dulcians were unsuitable of slave labour.
Dulkis 星人不适合作为奴隶劳工
- But then they'll leave us in peace!
- Well, no.
- 那他们就会安静地走开！  - 但是, 不是
They said you'll all die with your planet.
他们说你们会同你们的星球一同死亡
Surely they don't mean to destroy Dulkis completely?
他们的意思应该不是要完全毁灭 Dulkis 吧？
- DOCTOR: I'm afraid they do.
- But why? What do they want?
- 恐怕是的  - 但是为什么？他们想要什么？
A large amount of fuel for their invasion fleet.
为他们的侵略舰队提供大量的燃料
But we know that there are no minerals worth having,
但我们知道这里没有他们需要的矿物
at least not on this side of the island.
至少在岛上的这边没有
They're not mining for minerals
or any natural fuel source.
他们不是在采集矿物, 也不需要任何天然的燃料
But their spaceships use atomic power.
We've established that.
但他们的飞船用的是核能, 我们已经推断出来了
But there was no reactor in that ship of theirs,
但他们那艘飞船里面没有反应器
only a radiation storage unit.
只有一个辐射存储单元
You remember how when they landed
你记得不, 他们降落时
it sucked up all the radioactive dust
from the island?
它把这个岛上的放射性尘埃全都吸走了
Yes. So you're saying
that they store radioactive particles
记得, 所以你是说他们把放射性粒子存储起来了
and then convert that energy into power.
然后把它们转换成动力？
Exactly!
正是！
Well, then why are they drilling?
那, 他们为什么要钻孔呢？
Look, I'll show you.
看, 我来跟你展示一下
There are four drill holes
here, here, here and here,
有四个钻孔, 在这里、这里、这里和这里
and one drill hole in the centre.
还有一个钻孔在中间
Now, then, they have rockets mounted
in each of these drill holes,
现在, 他们把火箭装到各个钻孔上
and the centre drill hole is probably
for that atomic seed device.
而中间那个钻孔很可能就是原子播种装置
Oh.
噢
Well, don't you see?
嗯, 明白了吗？
They've chosen this spot because
the crust of the planet is thin.
他们选这个地点是因为这个星球的地壳很薄
They're going to fire the rockets through the crust
他们打算发射火箭穿透地壳
into the magma, the molten core.
进入岩浆, 进而达到地核
ZOE: Then that will almost certainly
fracture the crust of the planet.
那几乎肯定会导致这个星球的地壳裂开
Exactly.
正是
But that will create a volcano.
但那会导致火山啊
And if they explode the atomic
seed device in the middle of that...
而如果他们在那里面引爆那个原子播种装置...
Yes, that's right, Zoe.
是的, 就是这样, Zoe
The whole planet will become one vast
molten mass of radioactive material,
整个星球都会成为一个巨大的放射性材料的熔融体
the fuel store for their fleet.
成为他们u舰队的燃料库
Well, we'll just have to stop them, then.
啊, 我们必须组织他们啊
DOCTOR: Oh, Jamie,
it's not as simple as that, is it?
噢, Jamie, 并没有那么简单的, 是吧？
If only I could get hold of
that atomic seed device,
如果我们能拿到那个原子播种装置
I might be able to defuse it.
我还是有可能拆除它的
Yes, then there'd only be a local
volcanic eruption on the island.
是, 那样的话就只会在这个岛上有个局部的火山爆发了
- Yes... - But how can we get to the device?
- 对...  - 但是我们怎样才能拿到那个装置呢？
Yes, that's the problem.
嗯, 问题就在这里
Doctor, I've just had an idea.
博士, 我有了一个主意
Shush a minute, Jamie, I'm trying to think.
嘘, 等等, Jamie, 我正在思考呢
- Yes, I know you are, but...  - Oh, Jamie!
- 是, 我知道你在思考, 但是... - 噢, Jamie!
Now, listen! Will you listen to me?
现在, 听着！你能听我说吗？
Now, there's a dead-easy way
to get that device thing.
看, 现在有一个非常简单的方法搞到那个设备
- Really?  - Yes, now listen.
- 真的？  - 是的, 听我说
You said they were going to drop it
down the centre hole,
你刚才说他们打算把它扔进中间的钻孔
the one they're drilling outside here.
也就是他们在这里钻的那个
- Right?  - DOCTOR: Yes.
- 对吧？  - 对
Well, it's simple, isn't it?
那, 就简单了, 对不？
All we've got to do is dig a tunnel
through from here to the borehole
我们要做的事情, 就是挖一条隧道, 从这里到那个矿洞
and catch the seed device thing on its way down!
在那个设备下来的时候把它接住！
Oh. Well, it was just an idea.
噢, 但是, 这只是一个想法
But Jamie...
但是, Jamie
It's a brilliant idea!
这是个很神的想法！
It's so simple,
only you could have thought of it.
这个想法如此简单, 只有你才能想到
Oh! Hey?
噢！怎么？
We can get the direction from the periscope.
我们可以从潜望镜里面看好方向
Just line it up with the drilling site.
往钻孔点画一条线
Yes, there's only one snag, though.
Could we complete the tunnel in time?
是的．但还是有一个问题：我们能及时挖通隧道吗？
It'd have to be 12 feet long or more.
至少得有１２英尺
Well, Cully and I could delay
the Dominators' work up there.
这样, Cully 和我可以在上面拖延统领者的工作
ZOE: How?
怎么拖延？
Oh, we're getting very good
at destroying Quarks, aren't we?
噢, 我们很擅长消灭那些夸克, 对吧？
Yes, certainly seems to stop them working.
对, 至少让它们停止工作没有问题
DOCTOR: Yes, that's true,
but you've been lucky so far.
是, 你说得对．但到目前位置你们只是幸运
If only I could devise some sort of weapon for you.
要是我能帮你们设计出某种武器就好了
- Is there anything down here, Cully?
- No, I doubt it.
- 这里有什么东西不, Cully?  - 没, 我怀疑没有
Nothing but survival rations and medical kit.
除了救生口粮和医疗包, 什么也没有
Medical kit? Oh!
医疗包？噢！
It's surprising what you can do
你都想不到我能做些什么
with a few simple chemicals and a little ingenuity.
单凭几种简单的化学品和一点点聪明才智就可以了
Now, come on, we must dig this tunnel.
来, 快点, 我们必须开挖隧道了
- Zoe, give us a direction, will you?  - Right.
- Zoe, 帮我们定一下方向, 好吗？  - 好
On a line from...here.
沿着...这条线
Right! We start the tunnel there.
Get that bunk away, come on.
好！我们从这里开挖, 把那个东西搬走, 快点
That's it, Cully. I'll start with a knife, now...
就这样, Cully．我先用小刀, 看...
This line here.
这条线
I think you'd better let me start it, Jamie.
我觉得你最好让我来开场, Jamie
How are you going to dig through there
with your sonic screwdriver?
你打算用你那个音速起子来挖开这里？
It's a little more than a screwdriver.
Just watch this.
这可不仅仅是一把起子, 看着
(AMAZED CHATTERING, INDISTINCT)
- It's burning straight through!
- Aye, the Doctor's very good.
- 直接就烧穿了  - 啊, 博士很厉害
- Have you finished?  - Yes, just completed.
- 你完成了吗？  - 是的, 刚完成
Good. I shall enjoy destroying
this planet and its creatures.
很好．我要享受一下毁灭这个星球及其生物的过程
Get the seed device.
We will delay no longer.
取那个种子设备, 我们不能再拖延了
Can you see the borehole yet, Jamie?
你能看到矿洞了吗, Jamie?
JAMIE: The ceiling keeps caving in.
顶上开始垮塌了
ZOE: They're coming back!
他们回来了！
Toba's bringing the seed device.
Toba 带着种子设备朝这边来呢
Oh, dear.
噢, 天啦
You will recall all Quarks from their positions
你去把夸克从它们当前位置召回来
and prepare the craft for takeoff.
为飞船起飞做准备
Command accepted.
命令已接受
I will insert the seed device.
我去加入种子设备
Prime the rockets at perimeter boreholes.
将火箭装填到四周的钻孔上
Command accepted.
命令已接受
Very soon we shall see this planet die,
and its creatures with it.
很快我们就能看到这个星球的灭亡了, 连同它的生物一起
Shall I report to Fleet Leader?
要我报告给舰队首领吗？
Inform him the Dominator fleet
may approach on its refuelling orbit.
通知他说统领者舰队可以靠近能量补给轨道了
Command accepted. Quarks, follow.
命令已接受．夸克, 跟上
(QUARKS BLEEPING)
Quickly, Doctor!
快点, 博士！
He's taking the device out of its case now.
他正在把那个装置从箱子里取出来
Oh, Jamie, he'll be too late!
He's putting it in now.
哦, Jamie, 他快来不及了！他要把它放进去了
- It's gone! - DOCTOR: Oh!
- 不见了！  - 噢！
JAMIE: Doctor, have you caught it?
博士, 你接住了吗？
- Oh, Doctor!  - He's coming!
- 噢, 博士！  - 他过来了！
JAMIE: Quick, out.
快, 出去
Well?
怎样？
(LAUGHING)
- Oh, thank goodness!
- We're saved! We're saved, then!
- 噢, 感谢老天！  - 我们得救了, 我们得救了啊！
No, not just yet.
不, 还没有
I've still got to defuse it
before they explode it.
我还得拆除它, 赶在他们引爆它之前
- Oh! Oh, my word!  - ZOE: What?
- 噢！哦, 老天！  - 什么？
Well, it's sealed! It's completely sealed!
啊, 它是封死的！它是完全封死的！
I can't possibly undo it!
我没可能拆除它了！
You mean, all that was for nothing?
We're still going to get blown up?
你是说, 我们的努力都白费了？我们还是会被炸上天？
Yes, I'm afraid so,
unless I can think of some way
是的, 恐怕是, 除非我们想到什么方法...
of getting it off the planet without a...
能够离开这个星球而不...
Have you thought of something?
你是想到什么了吗？
Well, there is a way of getting it off the planet
啊, 的确有一种方法可以离开这个星球
without it doing any harm to any of us at all.
而不对我们所有人造成任何伤害
ZOE: Well, how?
哦, 什么方法？
Ah! But it's not going to be easy...
啊！但可能没有那么容易...
What? What are you going to do?
是什么？你打算怎么做？
Now, just leave it to me, Jamie, hmm?
得, 就交给我吧, Jamie, 嗯？
You, Zoe go back to the Tardis.
你, Zoe, 都回到 TARDIS 去
RAGO: Is all prepared?
都准备好了吗？
Yes, just two more Quarks to arrive.
是的, 就等最后两个夸克到了
Start takeoff procedure.
开始准备起飞
Command accepted.
命令已接受
(CAPSULE BEEPING)
Oh, where is he?
噢, 他在哪儿？
The Dominators' ship, it's away!
统领者的飞船, 开走了！
- Oh!  - Where's the Doctor?
- 噢！  - 博士在哪儿？
Doctor!
博士！
- Hey, where's the bomb thing?
- Oh, did you get rid of it?
- 嘿, 那个炸弹呢？  - 你甩掉它了吗？
- Well, where is it?
- (PANTING) Don't ask so many questions.
- 诶, 它在哪里？  - 别一下问这么多问题
- What?  - There's no time.
- 什么？  - 没有时间了
(EXPLOSIONS)
What's that?
那是什么？
It's the rockets in the other perimeter holes.
是四周那几个钻孔里的火箭
Come along, we'd better get inside the Tardis.
都过来, 我们最好进到 TARDIS 里面去
There's going to be an...
这里会有一场...
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Toba!
Toba!﻿
Doctor, come on, will you?
The whole place is going to blow up!
博士, 快点, 好吗？这里全部都要爆炸了！
Oh, it's quite all right, Jamie.
The planet is quite safe.
噢, 完全没事的, Jamie．这个星球非常安全
There's just going to be
a localised volcanic eruption.
只会有一场局部的火山爆发
It'll only affect the island.
只会影响这个小岛
Maybe so, but we happen to be on the island.
也许是, 但我们恰巧就在这个岛上
Oh, my word! Oh, oh!
哦, 真是！噢, 哦！